So let's continue our road to a pure action creator focused world by also outsourcing the burger builder
Bu yzden, hamburger reticisi ve sipari eylemi yaratcs kodunun d kaynak kullanmyla dardan bir eylem yaratcs
and the order action creator code into sagas
odakl dnyaya devam edelim. Burger reticisi ile
Let's start with the burger builder,
balayalm, burger oluturucu eylem
if we analyze the burger builder action creator file, it's very simple,
yaratcs dosyasn analiz edersek, ok basit, Orada zaten ok
we got a lot of pure action creators in there already,
sayda saf eylem ierik oluturucu var,
so action creators which just do that, create an action.
bu yzden bunu yapan eylem oluturucular bir eylem oluturur.
But we got one action creator initIngredients which actually runs some asynchronous code which executes
Ama aslnda bir yan etkisi yrten baz ezamansz kod altran bir eylem yaratcs initIngredients var, bu
a side effect,
yzden, ben yeni
so for that, I'll create a new file in the sagas folder BurgerBuilder.js. In there, I'll create my
bir dosya BurgerBuilder sagas klasrnde oluturacam. js. Orada, jeneratr fonksiyonu ihra
initIngredients saga which will be exported generator function,
edilecek olan initIngredients destann oluturacam, adndan sonra
add saga after the name, we'll get our action in there and now I'll take the code from initIngredients
destan ekleyeceiz, biz de oradaki eylemimizi alacaz ve imdi initIngredients'dan kodu alp BurgerBuilder'a
and put it into the BurgerBuilder.js
koyacam. js
file here.
dosyas burada.
Now we do use axios here
imdi burada eksenler
but if we go back to the burger builder file in the actions folder, we see that we actually import axios
kullanyoruz, ancak eylemler klasrndeki burger oluturucu dosyasna geri dnersek, aslnda zel
from our custom instance, so that we use our custom axios instance from the axios orders file.
rneimizden eksenler aldmz grrz, bylece zel eksenlerimizi aksios siparileri dosyasndan kullanrz.
So I'll use the same import here in my saga file because I obviously want to use the same instance of
Ben de ayn ithalat benim saga dosyamda kullanacam nk akas buradaki
axios here, that means we can also get rid of it in the BurgerBuilder.js file in the actions folder.
ayn akslarn rneini kullanmak istiyorum, yani BurgerBuilder'da bundan kurtulabiliriz. eylemler klasrnde js dosyas.
Now back in the BurgerBuilder.js file in the sagas folder, we import axios,
imdi BurgerBuilder'da. sagas klasrnde js dosyas, auth'a bir
now if we have a look at the auth.js file, we see that we also probably should import put from redux
gz atabilirsek, imdi akslar ithal ediyoruz. js dosyas, biz de muhtemelen destanmzdan gelen
saga effects so that we can dispatch actions from within our saga.
eylemleri gnderebilmemiz iin redux destan efektlerinden ithal etmemiz gerektiini gryoruz.
So let me add this import here too and with that, I'll use the same approach as we did earlier,
yleyse bu ithalat da buraya ekleyeyim, daha nce yaptmz gibi ayn yaklam
I'm going to store the response here in the response constant and use yield to wait for it to be returned
kullanacam, cevab burada sabit olarak saklayacam ve geri dn beklemek iin otomatik olarak kullanacam.
and to automatically get the data
bu szn bize verdii cevaplar bir
this promise gives us once it resolves and to also handle handle a failure, I'll wrap it with try.
kez zd zaman zmesi ve bir hata saptamas ile uramas durumunda, bunu denemem gerekecek.
So I'll try to get my constant, my response here I should say
Bu yzden, sabitimi elde etmeye alacam, cevabm burada sylemeliyim ama eer
but if that fails, well then we will go into the catch block here and catch any error we might have
bu baarsz olursa, o zaman burada yakalama blouna gideceiz ve olabilecek herhangi bir hatay yakalayacaz
and then handling it in the block thereafter.
ve daha sonra blokta ele alacaz.
Now the only things I do is I do dispatch something,
imdi yaptm tek ey bir ey gndermem,
so in the saga world, we do this by yielding a put call and what we do put is of course our action
bu yzden destan dnyasnda, bunu bir ar yapmak ve yaptmz ey elbette eylem
creator calls here where we pass on the data we got. For that, I'll need to import them so I'll import everything
yaratcmzn elimizdeki veriyi aktardmz yerlere armasdr. Bunun iin onlar ie aktarmam gerekecek, bylece her
as actions from
eyi eylemler olarak ie aktaracaz
and now let's go to the actions folder and there to the index file which we can also import
ve imdi eylemler klasrne gidelim ve dizin klasrne gidelim ki,
just like that by just referring to the folder as a whole. And then I can yield put actions and now setIngredients
sadece bir btn olarak klasre atfta bulunarak . Ve sonra put eylemleri verebiliyorum ve imdi
is required here, for that
setIngredients burada gereklidir,
we should make sure that in the index.js file in the actions folder, setIngredients is actually provided,
bunun iin endekste olduundan emin olmalyz. eylemler klasrnde js dosyas, setIngredients aslnda salanm, u
it currently is not,
anda deil, o
so let's add it as an export from the burger builder file in there, setIngredients. We also have
yzden buradaki burger oluturucu dosyasndan exportIn olarak ekleyelim setIngredients. Biz de buraya gelemiyoruz. Ayrca
fetchIngredients failed here,
bunu hamburger
we should also export this from burger builder,
reticisinden de ihra etmeliyiz,
so let's add this too. With these two exports added, we can go back to our saga and dispatch actions set
bu yzden bunu da ekleyelim. Bu iki ihracatn eklenmesiyle, destanmza geri dnebilir ve eylemleri
ingredients, pass on the response data,
dzenleyebiliriz, yant verisini iletebiliriz, kime bahanesi
whoops excuse me, up here of course
olursa olsun, tabiki buraya
so pass on the response data or in the error case, put actions.fetchIngredientsFailed,
kadar cevap verisini iletin veya hata durumunda, eylemler koyun. fetchIngredientsFailed, ayrca bunu altrdnzdan emin
make sure to also execute
olun, daha
that, you can then remove the then catch code down there.
sonra oradaki catch kodunu kaldrabilirsiniz.
This is our newly created saga,
Bu yeni yaratlan
let's now go back to index.js down there and let's register it, and for this, I'll export a new generator
destan, imdi dizine geri dnelim. Js aada ve hadi kaydolalm, ve bunun iin, ben btn
here which I'll name watchBurgerBuilder to group all burger builder related code.
burger reticisi ile ilgili kodu gruplandrmak iin watchBurgerBuilder adn vereceim yeni bir jeneratr ihra edeceim.
Technically we could add it here too and we could have one big watch function or generator but I'll like
Teknik olarak biz de buraya ekleyebiliriz ve byk bir saat ilevi veya jeneratr olabilirdik ama birden ok
to have multiple ones
tanesine sahip olmak istiyorum
and then, I will also import my sagas,
ve sonra da sagmalarm da ithal ediyorum, burada sadece
here it is only one but could be more from ./BurgerBuilder
bir tane var ama daha fazlas olabilir. / BurgerBuilder
and that one saga we do have of course is the
ve yaptmz bir destan,
initIngredients saga.
initIngredients destan.
So in watchBurgerBuilder,
Dolaysyla, WatchBurgerBuilder'da, TakeEvery
I will yield
eylem trlerini
takeEvery action types
elde edeceim ve imdi eylem
and now I need a new action type which we actually dispatch in the burger builder file in the action
yaratcs veya eylemler klasrndeki burger oluturucu dosyasnda gnderdiimiz yeni bir
creator or in the actions folder.
eylem trne ihtiyacm var.
So the action we actually create here now because I no longer want to return dispatch and run async
Yani imdi burada oluturduumuz eylem, artk gnderimi geri dndrmek istemiyorum ve async kodunu altrmak
code in there, I just want to create an action instead.
istemiyorum, sadece bunun yerine bir eylem oluturmak istiyorum.
So let's create a new action type for that, I'll create a constant here in the action types
Bunun iin yeni bir ilem tr oluturalm, INIT_INGREDIENTS olarak
folder which I'll name
isimlendireceimiz eylem trleri
INIT_INGREDIENTS, so just as the action creator is called then, INIT_INGREDIENTS,
klasrnde bir sabit oluturacam, bylece eylem oluturucunun
like this and in the action creator, in the burger builder file in the actions folder,
arld gibi, INIT_INGREDIENTS, bunun gibi ve eylem yaratcsnda eylemler klasrndeki burger
I'll set the type to actionTypes.INIT_INGREDIENTS.
oluturucu dosyas, tr actionTypes olarak ayarlayacam. INIT_INGREDIENTS.
So this is the action type to which you want to listen,
Yani bu, dinlemek istediiniz
so in the index.js file, I'll listen to actionTypes.INIT_INGREDIENTS and I will execute the initIngredientsSaga
eylem tipidir, yani endekste. js dosyas, actionTypes dinleyeceim. INIT_INGREDIENTS ve bu
whenever this occurs.
gerekletiinde initIngredientsSaga'y yrteceim.
The final step is to also call this newly created generator function here from our index.js file
Son adm, bu yeni oluturulmu jeneratr ilevini de dizinimizden armaktr. js dosyas bizim uygulama kk dzeyine
on the root level of our application so to say, there where we have saga middleware run watch off,
sylemek, orada biz destan middleware altrmak izlemek kapal, ben de destan
I'll also add saga middleware run
middleware altrmak eklemek ve
and now let's import this from our sagas folder to watch burger builder,
imdi bu burger oluturucu izlemek iin bizim sagas klasrnden ithalat
this saga here should also be run at the start
yapalm, bu destan burada da olmaldr balangta burada
without parentheses here. Let's save all of that
parantez olmadan altrlmaldr. Tm bunlar saklayalm ve
and this looks good,
bu iyi
we still initialize our ingredients here successfully.
grnyor, biz hala malzemelerimizi baaryla balatyoruz.
If I reload this application one more time, we see setIngredients is dispatched here and we do set
Eer bu uygulamay bir kez daha tekrar yklersem, setIngredients'n buraya
the ingredients and this works because we have our burger builder saga where we yield setIngredients.
gnderildiini gryoruz ve malzemeleri hazrlyoruz, nk bu setIngredient'leri verdiimiz burger yapc destanmz var.
If I comment it out here, you see we got an infinite loading screen because we never set the ingredients
Buraya yorum yaparsam sonsuz bir ykleme ekranmz olduunu gryorsunuz, nk malzemeleri hi bir zaman ayarlamadk,
so we can really say that our saga is working correctly here.
bylece destanmzn burada doru bir ekilde altn syleyebiliriz.
Let me comment it back in.
Tekrar yorum yapmama izin verin.